Guide to the Ann Imlah Schneider Papers, 1959-2014 and undated RL.11715
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Publications, 1959-2014 and undated
  - To Touch the Future: Transforming the Way Teachers Are Taught, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Touching the Future: Final Report, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Towards a Common European Framework for Reporting Language Competency, 1992 April (Box 3, Folder 17)
    by Rolf Schärer and Brian North
  - Towards Transnational Competence, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - The Training of, and U.S. Business' Needs for, International Specialists, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Undergraduate International Studies on the Eve of the 21st Century, 1994 December; 2 copies (Box 3, Folder 19)
    by Louis W. Goodman, Kay King, and Nancy L. Ruther
  - A University Turns to the World: A Personal History of the Michigan State University International Story, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    by Ralph H. Smuckler
  - U.S. Office of Education Programs Abroad, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Reprint
    By Robert Leestma
  - Western European Studies in the United States, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    by Stephen Blank
  - What We Can't Say Can Hurt Us: A Call for Foreign Language Competence by the Year 2000, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - What Works for Latino Students in Higher Education: 2009 Compendium Profiles of Selected Programs (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Where Credit is Due: Approaches to Course and Credit Recognition Across Borders in U.S. Higher Education Institutions, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Where Faculty Live: Internationalizing the Disciplines, 2006 April (Box 3, Folder 21)
    by Madeleine F. Green and Robert Shoenberg
  - Articles, 1959-2013; 5 folders (Box 6)
- Research Files, 1971-1999
  Arranged chronologically.
  Includes research on international education and foreign languages, area studies, Title VI, and governmental regulations.
  - Experiments in International Education, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Lambert Study, 1971 (Box 6)
  - Title VI Histories, Data, 1975-2009 (Box 6)
  - Rand Draft Comments, 1980 (Box 6)
  - AIS "Bibliography" (USED), 1982-1992 (Box 6)
  - UISFL Study, 1992-1998 (Box 6)
  - Reg[ister] Exercise, 1995-1996 (Box 6)
  - EDGAR Regulations, 1995-2007 (Box 6)
  - Archives and Title VI, 1995-2013 (Box 6)
  - Int. Ed. Research UG program evaluation, 1996-1999 (Box 7)
- Higher Education Files, 1970-2000
  Comprises files regarding Schneider's work with Title VI higher education centers for international and area studies. Topics include program planning and evaluation, budgets, and language enrollment.
  - Key Program Planning Docs, 1970-1974 (Box 7)
  - Evaluation, 1970-1975 (Box 7)
  - Program Planning--Manpower, 1972 (Box 7)
  - FY72 Centers, 1972 (Box 7)
  - Citizen Education, 1972-1980 (Box 7)
  - T6 Grad. Int. Studies Prog., 1972-1981 (Box 7)
  - FY73 Priorities, Analyses, 1973 (Box 7)
  - FY73 Centers Competition, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Evaluation Plans FY74, 1974 (Box 7)
  - T6 Center Data--Degrees etc., 1974-1995 (Box 7)
  - T6 Competition Results Info., 1975-2000 (Box 7)
  - Language Enrollment Data, 1982 (Box 7)
  - Title VI Undergraduate Education Programs, 1982-1985 (Box 7)
  - FLAS Data, 1984-1995 (Box 7)
  - T6 Center Budgets, 1985-1995 (Box 7)
  - T6 and Undergraduates, 1991 (Box 7)
  - CIE/OPE Issues, 1992-1995 (Box 7)
- Program Files, 1972-2006
  Includes Schneider's files related to the Center for Education within the U.S. Department of Education. The files relate primarily to appropriations, with some information on administration, analysis, and allocations. There are also files related to the Department's Committee on the Status of Women (1972-1973), the Presidential Commission on Language and International Studies (1977-1979), and Schneider's conference attendance.
  - Committee on the Status of Women, 1972-1973; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Title IX, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Conferences, 1974 (Box 7)
  - Wingspread Conference, 1974-1975; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - FY74-75 Appropriation, 1974-1975 (Box 7)
  - Arlie House Conference, 1975 (Box 7)
  - FY79 Appropriation, 1979 (Box 7)
  - Presidential Commission, 1977-1979 (Box 7)
  - FY80 Admin., Analyses, Appropriation, 1980 (Box 7)
  - FY81 Appropriation, Admin., 1981 (Box 7)
  - FY82 Appropriation, Admin., 1982 (Box 7)
  - FY83 Appropriation and Allocations, 1983 (Box 7)
  - FY84 Appropriation, 1984 (Box 7)
  - FY85 Appropriation, 1985 (Box 7)
  - FY85 Appropriation/Allocations, 1985 (Box 7)
  - FY87 Appropriation, 1987 (Box 7)
  - FY88 Appropriation, 1988 (Box 7)
  - FY89 Appropriation, 1989 (Box 7)
  - FY90 Appropriation, 1990 (Box 7)
  - FY91 Appropriation, 1991 (Box 7)
  - FY92 Appropriation, 1992 (Box 7)
  - FY93 Appropriation, 1993 (Box 7)
  - FY94 Appropriation, 1994 (Box 8)
  - FY95 Appropriation, 1995 (Box 8)
  - FY96 Appropriation, 1996 (Box 8)
  - FY97 Appropriation, 1997 (Box 8)
  - Title VI 40th Anniversary, 1998? (Box 8)
  - Center for Strategic & International Studies, 2002? (Box 8)
  - The Council of Chief State School Officers, 2006